Finding aid to the Smith Club of Kansas City, MO records CA.MS.00333
Smith College Archives
Smith Club of Kansas City, MO records
1948-2004
Smith College Archives
Smith Club of Kansas City, MO
CA.MS.00333
1.667 linear feet (4 containers)
The Smith Club of Kansas City, MO was founded in the 1940s; the club's earliest directory dates from 1948. Its records contain minutes, correspondence, clippings, newsletters, and photographs.
Biographical / Historical
The Smith Club of Kansas City, MO was founded in the 1940s; the club's earliest directory dates from 1948. The main functions of the Club are to arrange social events for the alumnae in the area and to fundraise for Smith Fund scholarships through their annual Art Forum which features lectures and a luncheon at the local museum. The Candidate's Committee recruits for Smith College in the Kansas City area through informational and social events and book awards.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains Club notebooks, President's files, Club newsletters, correspondence with the Smith College Alumnae Association (AASC), membership directories, files of Club events including the Club's annual Art Forum fundraiser. The President's files contain correspondence, clippings, photographs, Alumnae Council reports, minutes, mailings, and information on membership and events, specifically financial reports, chairman's reports, minutes, and other materials concerning the Club's annual Art Forum fundraiser. The Club notebooks contain mailings, newsletters, clippings, and photographs. The papers concentrate mainly on the Club's activities and records from the 1970s and 1980s.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Smith Club of Kansas City, MO Records were donated over a period of time to the Smith College Archives from a variety of sources.
- Club Notebook (2 folders), 1976-93 (Box 1)
- Club Notebook, 1981-96 (Box 1)
- Club Notebook, 1985-97 (Box 1)
- President's File, 1955-60 (Box 1)
- President's File, 1964-65 (Box 1)
- President's File, 1967-68 (Box 1)
- President's File, 1969-71 (Box 1)
- President's File (2 folders), 1974-75 (Box 1)
- President's File, 1975-76 (Box 1)
- President's File, 1976-77 (Box 1)
- Articles and Bylaws, 1974-1995 (Box 1)
- President's File, 1977-78 (Box 2)
- President's File, 1978-79 (Box 2)
- President's File (2 folders), 1979-80 (Box 2)
- President's File (2 folders), 1980-81 (Box 2)
- President's File (2 folders), 1981-82 (Box 2)
- President's File, 1989 (Box 2)
- President's File, 1992-95 (Box 2)
- President's File, 2001-02 (Box 2)
- President's File, 2003 (Box 2)
- Annual Meeting Minutes and Mailings, 1968-99; undated (Box 2)
- Executive Committee Minutes, 1981; 1990; undated (Box 2)
- Smith Club Strategic Planning Committee Roster, undated (Box 2)
- Treasurer's Reports and Correspondence, 1971-94 (Box 2)
- Dues Statements, 1992-93 (Box 2)
- Alumnae Council Reports, 1988-89 (Box 2)
- Candidate's Committee Report, 1992 (Box 2)
- Dues Statements, 1992-1993 (Box 2)
- Correspondence with AASC: General, 1982-2003 (Box 3)
- Correspondence with AASC: Annual Report, 1992-93 (Box 3)
- Correspondence with AASC: R.A.C.E. Kit, 1968 (Box 3)
- Correspondence re: Taggart Memorial Gift, 2002 (Box 3)
- Correspondence with Students, 1988; undated (Box 3)
- Directories, 1948-49; 1969-2004 (Box 3)
- Bills and Correspondence re: Directory 1984 (Box 3)
- Ivy League Association, 1984 (Box 3)
- Networking Notes and Responses to Smith Survey, 1980 (Box 3)
- Newsletters, 1974-97 (Box 3)
- Newsletters from other Smith Clubs, 1995-97 (Box 3)
- Survey re: Club and Art Forum, 1999 (Box 3)
- Events: General, 1989; undated (Box 3)
- Art Forum, 1968 (Box 3)
- Art Forum, 1976 (Box 3)
- Art Forum, 1977 (Box 3)
- Art Forum, 1979 (Box 3)
- Art Forum, 1980 (Box 3)
- Art Forum, 1982 (Box 3)
- Art Forum, 1983 (Box 3)
- Art Forum, 1984 (Box 4)
- Art Forum, 1985 (Box 4)
- Art Forum, 1987 (Box 4)
- Art Forum, 1988 (Box 4)
- Art Forum, 1990 (Box 4)
- Art Forum, 1991 (Box 4)
- Art Forum, 1992 (Box 4)
- Art Forum, 1993 (Box 4)
- Art Forum, 1994 (Box 4)
- Art Forum, 1995 (Box 4)
- Art Forum, 1996 (Box 4)
- Art Forum, 1997 (Box 4)
- Art Forum, 1998 (Box 4)
- Art Forum, 1999 (Box 4)
- Art Forum, 2000 (Box 4)
- Art Forum, 2001 (Box 4)
- Art Forum: Comparative Finances, 1972-85 (Box 4)
- Art Forum: Undated (Box 4)
- Centennial (Smith College), 1975 (Box 4)
- Jill Ker Conway Visit, 1984 (Box 4)
- Jill Ker Conway Visit, 1985 (Box 4)
- Garden Tour, 1960 (Box 4)
- Rally Day, 1982-83 (Box 4)
- Recollections, 1980 (Box 4)
- Clippings, 2001 (Box 4)
- Tour of Kansas City - "Gold Key", 1967-1968 (Box 4)